vacu.org 2019-06-22

# Privacy | Virginia Credit Union

Welcome to the new vacu.org! 

## Privacy Policy

Serving your needs and protecting your personal information are priorities for Virginia Credit Union (referenced herein as "Virginia Credit Union," "we," "us" or "our").

For purposes of this Policy, "online" means utilization of an internet communication protocol to view, display, access, receive or transmit information. This Policy covers all our online practices, including, but not limited to our VACU.org website, our Online Banking service, and our Mobile Banking service. Our separate Privacy Notice, along with this Policy, describes the privacy and data security practices that we follow.

### Accessibility and cookies

Cookies are pieces of data stored by your Web browser that are useful for expediting page loads or enhancing your online experience when you return to a website.

Although cookies do not reveal our members' identity, we use cookies to help us confirm our members' identities before granting access to our secure online banking system. To take full advantage of the level of security that we offer, your browser must meet certain requirements, such as supporting 128-bit encryption and being set to allow our servers to create a cookie on your system.

We also use Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting cookies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and gather aggregated demographic information. We may also contract with third-party companies who use cookies to measure the performance of a marketing effort on our behalf. We prohibit these companies from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than Virginia Credit Union. To opt-out of data from being used by Google Analytics, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Please contact us if you have any questions, comments, or concerns about the accessibility of any page on our website.

### Information collected when you view or visit our website

When you are simply viewing our website, we do not collect or retain any personal or identifiable information. However, for security purposes, and to respond to or fulfill your requests, we will collect and retain personal or identifiable information when you submit such to us, transact with us, or we provide you with access to your online account information.

We do collect non-identifying information for internal statistical purposes whenever you visit our website. This statistical information is collected in an effort to better enrich the online experience of our visitors, to assess what information is most and least important to our visitors, to analyze the effectiveness of our ads, and for determining whether our content and/or its presentment is useful and relevant to visitors of our website.

### What happens when you send information to us or transact with us online

Whenever you submit information to us using methods we make available to you on our website, we protect your information using administrative and technical processes along with strong industry standard encryption recommended for financial institutions. There is a serious risk that your information could be intercepted if you send information using a method outside of our website, such as sending an email from your home email server or posting a message to us through a social media website. To send us a secure message, you should only use the method provided on our Contact Us web page, or through our encrypted email service when instructed by us, or the method provided after logging on to our Online or Mobile Banking services.

For a full description of security measurements for transacting with us online and for specific browser requirements, please refer to our Online Banking Agreement and Electronic Funds Transfer Disclosure. For information regarding the use of our Mobile Banking Services, please refer to our Mobile Banking Services Addendum.

**Google Maps API:**  When accessing third-party Google Maps on our website, you are agreeing to Google’s [Terms of Service](https://developers.google.com/maps/terms) and [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

### How to stop or unsubscribe from receiving communication from us

If your email address or a phone number for receiving text messages is on record with us, we may periodically send you educational or informational communication about products, services or events that we believe may interest you. Instructions for how you can stop or unsubscribe from receiving these messages are included in each communication that we send. However, we will still communicate with you in connection with servicing your account, fulfilling your request or about any promotion, service or program in which you have elected to participate.

### Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

Unless verifiable consent acceptable to us is obtained from a parent or legal guardian, we do not knowingly collect, maintain or use personal information obtained from our website about children under 13 years of age. We are not responsible for the data collection or use practices of any party to which our website may link. For more information about the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), visit the Federal Trade Commission website, [www.ftc.gov](https://www.ftc.gov/).

### Links to other websites or when other websites display our advertisements

We are not responsible for the content, practices or policies of any other party or any non-VACU website you visit, including any social media sites in which we display information, or any website whose link appears within our website, and regardless of any affiliation we may share with any other entity. Before providing any personal or identifiable information, you should first review the policies of any website you are visiting. The fact that there is a link between our website and that of another website does not represent an endorsement by us of the content and any product, service, or program contained on any other website. Ads we place on other websites may contain a "tag," which is a code that tells us that our ad was reviewed at the sponsoring website. Tags do not contain personal or identifiable information and are only a marketing tool for measuring the effectiveness of placing our ads on other websites.

### Updates

Material changes to this Policy and updated versions of the VACU Privacy Notice will be posted on the Virginia Credit Union website. This Policy was last updated May 2018.

## Privacy Notice

Rev. 2/18

**FACTS** | **WHAT DOES VIRGINIA CREDIT UNION (VACU)    
DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**  
---|---  
**Why**? | Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
**What**? | The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income
  * Account balances and payment history
  * Credit history and credit scores

When you are no longer our member, we continue to share your information as described in this notice.  
  
**How**? | All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons Virginia Credit Union chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
Reasons we can share your personal information | Does VACU share? | Can you limit this sharing?  
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes**  \- such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus | Yes | No  
**For our marketing purposes**  \- to offer our products and services to you | Yes | No  
**For joint marketing with other financial companies** | Yes | No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes**  \- information about your transactions and experiences | Yes | No  
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes**  \- information about your creditworthiness | No | We don't share  
**For nonaffiliates to market to you** | No | We don't share  
Questions? | Call 804-323-6800 or 800-285-6609 or go to www.vacu.org  
---|---  
Who we are  
---  
Who is providing this notice? | Virginia Credit Union Inc., "VACU"  
What we do  
---  
How does Virginia Credit Union protect my personal information? | To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.  
How does Virginia Credit Union collect my personal information? | We collect your personal information, for example, when you 

  * open an account or deposit money
  * pay your bills or apply for a loan
  * use your credit or debit card

We also collect information from others such as credit bureaus, affiliates or other companies  
  
Why can't I limit all sharing? | Federal law gives you the right to limit only 

  * sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes - information about your creditworthiness
  * affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.  
  
Definitions  
---  
Affiliates | Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * Our affiliates include other companies such as Virginia CU Insurance Services LLC, Virginia CU Realty LLC and Virginia Statewide Title Services LLC.

Nonaffiliates | Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies 

  * VACU does not share with nonaffiliates so they can market to you

Joint Marketing | A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you. 

  * Our joint marketing partners include companies such as insurance companies, financial management companies.

Other Important Information  
---  
This notice supersedes all prior privacy notices.
